# Zuzanna Osika

PhD researcher: Explainable Al

📕 +48 791645562 osikazuzanna@gmail.com 🧥 Delft, NL

in /zuzanna-osika 😯 osikazuzanna.github.io

## **Profile**

Working on AI tools to enhance explainability and transparency for Public Policy Design, focusing on climate change policies. Specializing in addressing complex decision-making with diverse objectives and stakeholders. For publications, please refer to my Google Scholar.

# **Areas of Expertise**

Explainable AI - Reinforcement Learning - Multi-Objective Decision-Making - Transparent Decision-Making - Public Policy Design - Climate Change Adaptation - Data Science

# **Experience**

# PhD Condidate, (HIPPO Lab, Technical University Delft)

**Delft, NL** 04/2022 - present

- Utilizing AI (reinforcement learning) to tackle societal challenges (e.g. climate change), aiming to develop adaptive and transparent public policy solutions.
- Creating AI explainability tools to assist policy-makers in utilizing AI for decision-making processes.
- coordinator of a master's course: Interdisciplinary Advanced AI Project member of PhD Council member of working group
  on diversity and inclusion at TU Delft

## Socio-Economic Data Scientist (YGT), (European Space Agency)

Oxford, UK 09/2020 - 03/2022

- Developed web-based dashboards for data visualization. Utilized R, Python, and econometric models for data analysis impacting UN Sustainable Development Goals.
- Presented insights to the representatives of member states

## Junior Modelling Analyst, (Nielsen)

Warsaw, PL 10/2019 - 08/2020

- Performed econometric modeling and data analysis in FMCG industry.
- Automated data tasks in R.

#### Education

## MSc Computer Science and Econometrics University of Warsaw

Warsaw, PL 2018-2020

Thesis: Comparison of tree-based models' performance in prediction of marketing campaign results using Explainable Artificial Intelligence tools (working paper)

Exchange University of Bologna

Bologna, IT 2019

Exchange Student at the Department of Statistics. Relevant Courses: Non-parametric statistics, Methods and Tools for Official Statistics: Population and Health Statistics, Econometrics

BSc Computer Science and Econometrics University of Warsaw

Warsaw, PL 2015-2018

Thesis: Tertiary Education Levels and Earnings in Poland and Some Other OECD Countries (published paper)

#### Skills

- Technical & Software: Python (numpy, pytorch, pandas, gym, plotly), R (R shiny, plotly), SQL, Stata, Power BI,
   Adobe Illustrator, MS Office
- Interpersonal: Presentation of complex concepts in an approachable way, Leadership, Organized, Creative Problem-Solving, Active Listening & Empathy, Adaptability, Analytical Thinking

## Languages

• Polish [Native]

• Dutch [Basic] - Learning

• English [Advanced]